Guide to the Jan Van Dyke papers, 1964-2005 MS2111
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Jan Van Dyke papers
1964-2005
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Van Dyke, Jan
MS2111
7 Linear Feet
Collection documents the professional dance career of Jan Van Dyke, including performance files, correspondence, photographs, articles, audio-visual material, and publicity materials from the late 1960s to the 2000s.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Biographical Note
Jan Van Dyke (1941- ) is a dancer, choreographer, and teacher who was active in the dance community in Washington, D.C. in the years after her graduation from The George Washington University with an M.A. in dance education in 1967. That year, she founded the Georgetown Workshop dance studio with John Gamble. In 1970, she left Washington, D.C. for New York, where she studied with Merce Cunningham and at the Martha Graham and Alwin Nikolais schools. In 1972, she returned to Washington, D.C. and established her own dance studio, Dance Place, in Adams Morgan, which became the leader in modern dance training and performance in D.C. Van Dyke toured extensively throughout the United States with her dance company, Jan Van Dyke and Dancers, and as a solo artist. In 1980, she was honored by the Metropolitan Dance Association at their First Annual Dance Awards for her work and commitment to dance in the D.C. area. Later that year Van Dyke and four dancers from her company once again left DC for New York. She returned periodically to perform as a visiting artist and to help choreograph a production of the National Ballet.
Van Dyke and her dancers moved to San Francisco in 1982, where she was part of the faculty at the Footwork Studio. After three years in San Francisco, Van Dyke disbanded Jan Van Dyke and Dancers and moved to London for a teaching position at the Laban Centre for Movement and Dance. In the late 1980s, Van Dyke enrolled in the University of North Carolina in Greensboro and was awarded an in Ed.D. in Curriculum and Educational Foundations in 1989.
Over the span of her career, Jan Van Dyke has taught and performed throughout the United States and in various European countries, including Italy and Portugal. She is now an assistant professor in the dance department at the University of North Carolina in Greensboro, where she teaches courses in technique, choreography, repertory and dance administration. In 1993, she published Modern Dance in a Postmodern World: An Analysis of Federal Arts Funding and Its Impact on the Field of Modern Dance. Van Dyke and John Gamble have reunited and formed John Gamble/Jan Van Dyke Dance Company. She is also involved with the organization of the annual North Carolina Dance Festival. Her work has received grants from the DC Council for the Arts and Humanities, the California Council for the Arts, and the National Endowments for the Arts.
Collection Scope and Content
The Jan Van Dyke Collection documents the professional dance career of Jan Van Dyke, including performance files, correspondence, photographs, articles, audio-visual material, and publicity materials from the late 1960s to the 2000s.
The Jan Van Dyke Collection is part of the Dance Archives of the Greater Washington Region. The Archives was established in 1993 by Nancy Diers Johnson, Ed.D., Associate Professor of Dance, and the Gelman Library of The George Washington University. The Dance Archives of the Greater Washington Region collects, preserves and makes accessible the documentary heritage of all forms and types of dance.
Collection Organization
Organized in four series: Administrative files and photographs; Clippings, advertisements, articles, and audio-visual materials; Audio-visual materials, clippings, correspondence, programs and promotional materials; and Programs, brochures and articles.
Photographs; Choreographers; Teachers; Performances; Videocassettes; Dancers; New York (N.Y.); Washington (D.C.); George Washington University; Gamble, John; George Washington University--Alumni and alumnae
- Administrative files and photographs, 1974-2000; MS2111 Series 1; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 1, Box 2)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains administrative files (including performance files, publicity materials, and correspondence) and photographs documenting Jan Van Dyke's dance career from 1974 to 2000.
  - Administrative files and photographs, undated (Box 1)
    General note
  - Performance Files: Harford Community College Theatre, Bel Air, MD, 06/06/1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Performance Files: The Cubiculo, New York, NY, 11/11/1977-11/12/1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Performance Files: The Baltimore Museum of Art, Baltimore, MD, 12/04/1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Performance Files: Slayton House, Columbia, MD, 04/22/1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Performance Files: Marvin Center, George Washington University, Washington, DC, 04/28/1978-04/29/1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Performance Files: Hagerstown Junior College Arts Festival, Hargerstown, MD, 04/30/1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Performance Files: John Wright Theatre, California State University at Fresno, Fresno, CA, 05/10/1978-05/11/1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Performance Files: Maryland Center for the Arts, Saint Joseph's College, Emmitsburg, MD, 07/14/1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Performance Files: American Theatre Laboratory, New York, NY, 08/03/1978-08/05/1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Performance Files: Harford Community College Theatre, Bel Air, MD, 11/09/1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Performance Files: Hunter College Studio Theatre, New York, NY, 11/15/1978-11/16/1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Performance Files: Blackwell Auditorium, Ralph Macon College, Ashland, VA, 01/26/1979-01/27/1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Performance Files: Performance for the Candlelight Society, Wild Lake High School, Columbia, MD, 03/03/1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Performance Files: Corcoran Gallery of Art, Washington, DC, 03/30/1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Performance Files: Milwaukee Performing Arts Center, Milwaukee, WS, 07/09/1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Performance Files: Hawaii Dance Theatre, University of Hawaii, Honolulu, HI, 08/10/1979-08/12/1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Performance Files: The Winter's Tale, Arena Stage, Washington, DC, 10/05/1079-11/11/1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Performance Files: George Washington Hall, Mary Washington College, Fredericksburg, VA, 02/24/1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Performance Files: Hill Theater, Kenyon College, Gambler, OH, 04/25/1980 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Performance Files: Dolph Auditorium, Cincinnati, OH, 07/25/1980-07/26/1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Performance Files: City Dance Festival, Washington, DC, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Publicity Material: Biographical sheets/Performance lists, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Publicity Material: Brochures, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Publicity Material: Clippings/Articles, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Publicity Material: Flyers/Mailers, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Publicity Material: Poster, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Publicity Material: Press Releases, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Publicity Material: Programs, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Administrative files and photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", Jeff James (?), "Big Show,", 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", Jan Van Dyke, "Big Show," National Cathedral, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", Jan Van Dyke, "Big Show," National Cathedral, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Black and white photographs: 5" x 7", Jan Van Dyke, "Big Show," National Cathedral, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", Jan Van Dyke, "Big Show", undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", Jan Van Dyke, "Ceremony I", undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", Jean Jones, Valerie Shanks, Elly Canterbury, "Paradise Castle", undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", unidentified dancers, "Ceremony II with Roses", undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", Jan Van Dyke, "The Rose Garden", undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Black and white photographs: 7" x 10", Jan Van Dyke and unidentified dancer, "Fleetwood Mac Suite", undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", Shelly North, Elly Canterbury, Susan Sachs, Becky Slifken, and Jan Van Dyke, "Fleetwood Mac Suite", undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Black and white photographs: 7 ½" x 9 ½", unidentified dancers, "A Dance in Two Spaces", undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", Elly Canterbury and unidentified dancers, "A Dance in Two Spaces", undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", Shelly Leibman, Cathy Paine, and unidentified dancer, "Circling", undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", unidentified dancers, "Circling", undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", unidentified dancers, "Circling", undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", unidentified dancers, "Circling", undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", unidentified dancers, "Circling", undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", unidentified dancers, "Circling", undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", unidentified dancers, "Stamping Dance", undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", Jan Van Dyke, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Black and white photographs: 8" x 10", Elly Canterbury, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Administrative files and photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Poster: Oversize material: Jan Van Dyke Dance Group at the University of North Carolina, Greenboro Dance Theater, 01/12/2000-01/14/2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Clippings, advertisements, articles, and audio-visual materials, 1968-2002; MS2111 Series 2; 4 Linear feet (Box 4, Box 5, Box 8, Box 9, Box 6, Box 7, Box 12, Box 10, Box 11)
  This series contains clippings, advertisements, articles, and audio-visual media that document Jan Van Dyke's dance career from 1968 to 2002.
  - Clippings, advertisements, articles, and audio-visual materials., undated (Box 4)
    Formerly box 1 of accretion 2001
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper Clippings:, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Advertisement: Jan Van Dyke Group Postcard announcing a date of free Dance performance 06/09-06/10 (no year given), undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Advertisement: Poster of John Gamble and Jan Van Dyke Dance Company, NC, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Advertisement: Jan Van Dyke Modern Dance Workshop Dance Classes, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Advertisement: North Carolina Dance Festivals announcing dates, 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Advertisement: Invitation to The George Washington University Theatre and Dance "Women's work at GW dance legacy.", 03/26/1999 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Advertisement: Program for Jan Van Dyke Dancers at the Footwork Studio. Six Dances: Two Dances, Quartet, Pearl, Stamping Dance, Luna, and Spike, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Advertisement: Program for Jan Van Dyke and Dancers performing at Footwork Studio, 03/29/1985-03/31/1985 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Advertisement: The NC Dance Project Presents: The 6th Annual Gallery Performances Series The Jan Van Dyke Dance Group, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Advertisement: Flyer Announcing D.C works at Cubiculo evening of solos by Washington Area Artist Dance by Jan Van Dyke, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Advertisement: Jan Van Dyke and Dancers with Quotes, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Washington Dance Review: Issue Autumn 1985 Vol. 5, No. 1 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Washington Dance Review: Issue Autumn 1986 Vol. 6, No. 1 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Washington Dance Review: Issue Autumn 1980 Vol. 1, No. 5 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Washington Dance Review: Issue Spring 1987 Vol. 6, No. 3 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Washington Dance Review: Issue Summer 1986 Vol. 5, No. 4 by Kim Chan (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Contemporary Dance Theatre: 25th Anniversary Season Concert, 06/19/1998-06/20/1998 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Contemporary Dance Theatre: Footprints Vol. III No IV Winter, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Dance Magazine: "Antony Tudor will receive Capezio Award", undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Dance Magazine: "The Making of a Music Video Bop till you Drop," by Jan Van Dyke, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Manuscripts on Jan Van Dyke: 'Modern Dance in Postmodern World.' Preface and Chapter I: The Modern Point of View, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Manuscripts on Jan Van Dyke: 'Modern Dance in Postmodern World.' Chapter II: The Nation Endowment for the Arts and its Impact on Modern Dance: A Review of the Literature, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Manuscripts on Jan Van Dyke: 'Modern Dance in Postmodern World.' Chapter III: Dance and Education, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Manuscripts on Jan Van Dyke: 'Modern Dance in Postmodern World.' Chapter IV: Four dance Artists: The Perspective from the Filed, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Manuscripts on Jan Van Dyke: 'Modern Dance in Postmodern World.' Chapter V: Modern Dance in a Postmodern World, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Manuscripts on Jan Van Dyke: 'Modern Dance in Postmodern World.' Bibliography, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Miscellaneous: Jan Van Dyke Performances, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous: Clifton Magazine of The University of Cincinnati: The Performing Arts with Correspondence to Jan Van Dyke from Copy Editor Megan E. F. Jones, (winter 1987) (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke: Posing 1, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke: Posing 2, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke: Posing 3, undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke: Posing 4, undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke: Posing 5, undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke: Posing 6, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Clippings, advertisements, articles, and audio-visual materials., undated (Box 5)
    Formerly box 2 of accretion 2001
  - Photographs: "Waltz" by Van Dyke, photo by Jo Tartt - 1, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: "Waltz" by Van Dyke, photo by Jo Tartt - 2, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke leaping - 1, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke leaping - 2, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke leaping - 3, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke leaping - 4, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke jumping, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke dress swirling, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke on point, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke squatting, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke elevating, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke flexing, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke teaching a class, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke: dance series I-1, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke: dance series I-2, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke: dance series I-3, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke: dance series II-1, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke: dance series II-2, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke: dance series III-1, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke: dance series III-2, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke: dance series III-3, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke: dance series IV-1, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Photographs: Van Dyke: dance series IV-2, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Photographs: 2 Women dancing, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Photographs: Dancers in arabesque, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Photographs: 2 Female Dancers (from behind), undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Photographs: Man dancing 1, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Photographs: Man dancing 2, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Photographs: Woman standing by piano, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Photographs: Woman with arms extended, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Photographs: Dancers in the studio, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Photographs: 4 women dancing, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Photographs: Man in arabesque, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Photographs: 3 women holding hands, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Photographs: Performance: Series I-1, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Photographs: Performance: Series I-2, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Photographs: Performance: Series I-3, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Photographs: Performance: Series II, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Photographs: Man and woman looking at photo album, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Photographs: Man looking up, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Clippings, advertisements, articles, and audio-visual materials., undated (Box 6)
    Formerly box 3 of accretion 2001
  - Audio-visual materials: VHS: Karen and Alvin, The Long Goodbye (10min), undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Audio-visual materials: VHS: Spike: Contemporary Dance Theatre - Van Dyke, choreographer (18min), undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Audio-visual materials: VHS: Two Dances One Space: Performed by Van Dyke and Elly Canterbury (6min), 1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Audio-visual materials: VHS: Circling: Performed by Van Dyke at George Mason University (31min), 04/1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Audio-visual materials: VHS: Rhythm #4: Performed at The George Washington University by the Momentum Dance Theatre (10min), 07/25/1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, advertisements, articles, and audio-visual materials., undated (Box 7)
    Formerly box 4 of accretion 2001
  - Audio-visual materials: Beta: Woof and Ella, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Audio-visual materials: Beta: Van Dyke - Cincinnati performances of Duet, Passengers, Two Dances in One Space, Double Times, and Stamping, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Audio-visual materials: Beta: Footwork, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Audio-visual materials: Beta: Unlabeled, Maxwell Exitaxial Videocassette 250, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Audio-visual materials: Beta: Performances by Bach Duet, Two Dances, Passenger, Double Times, Stamping, Spike, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, advertisements, articles, and audio-visual materials., undated (Box 8)
    Formerly box 5 of accretion 2001
  - Audio-visual materials: Beta: Performances of A Formal Suite, Tiny Life, Lament, Section Stamping and a narration by Van Dyke, 03/1985 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Audio-visual materials: Beta: Footwork 1984, performances of Two Dances, Quartet, Pearl, Stamping, Luna, Spike, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Audio-visual materials: Beta: Washington Ballet, Washington Suite in Spring 1981. Performed by Van Dyke, Julie miles, Lynn Cote, Amanda McKerrow, Simon Dow, John Godling, and Sandra Broufman, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Audio-visual materials: Beta: Ella and Twilight with Van Duyke, dubs from 1977 and in black and white (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, advertisements, articles, and audio-visual materials., undated (Box 9)
    Formerly box 6 of accretion 2001
  - Audio-visual materials: U-matic: Van Dyke performs Variations on a Theme, Passengers, and solo excerpts from Fleetwood Mac, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Audio-visual materials: U-matic: A Dance in Two Spaces and Anne's Side, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Audio-visual materials: U-matic: A Dance in Two Spaces: Shelly's Side, Two Dances in one Space, and Waltz, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, advertisements, articles, and audio-visual materials., undated (Box 10)
    Formerly box 7 of accretion 2001
  - Audio-visual materials: U-matic: Van Dyke and John Gamble Dance Company performing Borderline, Untitled, Life and Times and Five Short Forms, 05/17/1992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Audio-visual materials: U-matic: Van Dyke Dances, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Audio-visual materials: U-matic: Van Dyke Talking Head, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Audio-visual materials: U-matic: Spike performed in 06/1983 by Laura Fly, P. Meagian, L. Scider, J. Smith and choreographed by Van Dyke (11min), undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Audio-visual materials: U-matic: Two Dances in One Space (7min) Quartet (10min) Pearl (9min) Stamping Dance (22min) Luna (8min) and Spike (11min) performed on 06/09/1984 by Van Dyke and Dancers (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Audio-visual materials: U-matic: Van Dyke Stamping Dance, 02/1980 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, advertisements, articles, and audio-visual materials., undated (Box 11)
    Formerly box 8 of accretion 2001
  - Audio-visual materials: Reel: Waltz, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Audio-visual materials: Reel: Van Dyke and Dancers at the Corcoran, 02/01/1975-02/08/1975 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Audio-visual materials: Reel: Van Dyke Solos Waltz and Big Show, Winter 1974 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Audio-visual materials: Reel: Van Dyke in Ella and Twilight, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Audio-visual materials: Reel: Van Dyke in Ceremony I, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Audio-visual materials: Reel: Van Dyke in Ceremony I and Paradise, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Audio-visual materials: Reel: Van Dyke in Variations (20min), 12/1978 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, advertisements, articles, and audio-visual materials., undated (Box 12)
    Formerly Box 2 of Dance Archives of the Greater Washington Region Collection (Van Dyke Accretion)
  - Audio-visual materials: VHS: The Life and Times... (1991); Five Short Forms (1992); A Little Late Afternoon Music (1992), 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    "Choreography by Jan Van Dyke. Performed by the Gamble/Van Dyke Dance Co."
- Audio-visual materials, clippings, correspondence, programs and promotional materials, 1964-2002; MS2111 Series 3; 1.25 Linear feet (Box 15, Box 14, Box 13, Box 12)
  This series contains clippings, articles, programs, brochures, photographs, and audio-visual media that document Jan Van Dyke's dance career from 1964 to 2002. The clippings consist of performance reviews and previews, profiles of Van Dyke and other dancers, and general articles about dance.
  - Audio-visual materials, clippings, correspondence, programs and promotional materials, undated (Box 12)
  - Audio-visual materials: VHS: Oldies, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    Five dances all choreographed between 1973 and 1978. Shown here in a Van Dyke retrospective show performed by Jan Van Dyke and Dancers in the Dance Project studio/theater at 2424 18th Street. Ceremony II, Paradise Castle, Ceremony I, Ella, Twilight. No sound.